{"tossups": [{"question": "This man\u2019s nomination to the Supreme Court resulted in the first public hearing held by the Senate Judiciary Committee. His opinion in<em> Packer Corporation v. Utah</em> created exceptions for free speech protections when there was a \u201ccaptive audience\u201d. This man is the alphabetically first author of the article\u201cThe Right to Privacy\u201d. This man opposed large trusts and oligarchs in his<em> Other People\u2019s Money and</em> <em>How the Bankers Use It</em>. He defended limits on women\u2019s working hours in a namesake evidence-filled\u201cBrief\u201d in<em> Muller v. Oregon</em>. For ten points, name this liberal Jewish Supreme Court justice.", "answer": "Louis<b> Brandeis</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Thedore Adorno argued that one of this author\u2019s works was a sweeping commentary which foresaw the terror of Nazi occupation. That work\u2019s protagonist meets the hapless Block after making fun of the title process and is murdered \u201clike a dog.\u201d The Bed, Harrow, and the Inscriber make up the \u201capparatus\u201din another story by this author, in which the Officer die while inscribing the saying \u201cBe Just\u201d into his back. Joseph K. was created by, for ten points, what Czech author of the stories \u201cIn the Penal Colony\u201dand \u201cThe Trial.\u201d", "answer": "Franz<b> Kafka</b>", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "At Laurence Olivier\u2019s funeral, an arrangement of a work of this composer by Christopher Palmer was played; that original work was titled for a William Dunbar poem. Paul Hindemith replaced Lionel Tertis to premiere a viola concerto by this composer dedicated to Christabel McLaren. This composer scored a 1944 film adaptation of<em> Henry V</em>. This composer\u2019s<em> Orb and Sceptre</em> and<em> Crown Imperial</em> were for written the coronations of Elizabeth II and George VI. For ten points, name this composer of<em> Belshazzar\u2019s Feast</em>.", "answer": "Sir William<b> Walton</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "One depiction of this battle shows Asher Crockett saving the life of a cousin of George Washington. The losing side of this battle was following up on false information about an attack on Ninety Six. Adding to a loss at the nearby Battle of King\u2019s Mountain, the this battle\u2019s outcome compelled General Cornwallis to fight the Battle of Guilford Courthouse. For ten points, name this American Revolutionary War battle, a defeat for Banastre Tarleton which took place in a South Carolina town named for its cattle housing.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Cowpens</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This scientist\u2019s landmark 1952 paper<em> The Education of a Computer</em> was written for the Remington Rand corporation, for which this scientist\u2019s team created the A-0 [a zero] system and its successors, including MATH-MATIC and FLOW-MATIC. The term \u201ccomputer bug\u201d dates from this scientist\u2019s work on the Mark II at Harvard. COBOL was developed by the students of, for ten points, what rear admiral in the US Navy whose early work on compilers was key in developing human-readable computer programming languages?", "answer": "Grace<b> Hopper</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Computer Science"}, {"question": "In 1977, this person became head of the Special Victims Bureau and earlier was appointed Assistant District Attorney for Queens, leading to cries of nepotism. This politician ran on the slogan, \u201cFinally, A Tough Democrat\u201d though thousands of dollars of loans from John Zaccaro were found to be illegal. Following a debate, Barbara Bush derided this person as a \u201cwitch\u201d. Ultimately, this person\u2019s running mate only won in Minnesota and the District of Columbia. In 1984, this person ran as the vice presidential candidate with Walter Mondale. The first woman to run for vice president for a major party was, for ten points, which New York Democrat?", "answer": "Geraldine<b> Ferraro</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Graham Greene\u2019s whiskey priest was a member of, for ten points, what largest religious institution in Mexico?", "answer": "Mexican Roman<b> Catholic Church</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "After Dr. Robert Whalen addressed concerns in this place, lawn signs appeared with the slogan\u201cGive me Liberty, I\u2019ve Already Got Death\u201d. Governor Hugh Carey promised a crowd in the 99th Street School that the state would buy back homes in this place, spurring activist efforts from Lois Gibbs. A report calling this place a \u201cpublic health time bomb\u201d came out after Jimmy Carter declared a federal emergency here. The Superfund program was created following the actions of a company who sold this place for a dollar in 1953, Hooker Chemical. For ten points, name this New York neighborhood where Hooker Chemical dumped massive amounts of toxic waste.", "answer": "<b> Love Canal</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A governor of this region had written elegies for his mistress Lycoris and was forced to commit suicide after building a monument in Philae to glorify himself. The priest Isidoris lost to Avidius Cassius during this region\u2019s Bucolic War. Gaius Petronius invaded south of this region to fight the kandake Amanirenas\u2019s Kingdom of Kush. This region exported grain to Rome and was bordered by Cyrenaica and the Sinai Peninsula. For ten points, name this region that Augustus took over from Cleopatra.", "answer": "Roman<b> Egypt</b> (or<b> Aegypta</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "One current party named for this ideology replaced its predecessor at the Alfortville Congress; that predecessor party with this ideology was called the SFIO and was created by a man who was assassinated for his pacifism at the outbreak of WWI, Jean Jaur\u00b4es. This ideology\u2019s first French government was achieved by the Popular Front, where parties with this ideology allied with the French Communist Party. For ten points, name this left-wing ideology whose current French party was led by Fran\u00b8cois Hollande.", "answer": "<b> socialism</b> (or<b> socialist</b>, do not accept or prompt on<b> communism</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Juan Gergorio Sarria assassinated this man at La Jacoba, an action ordered by Jos\u00b4e Maria Obando and which caused the exile of Francisco Santander. Despite being outnumbered by 2 to 1, this man defeated Jos\u00b4e de La Mar in the Battle of Tarqui. This second-in-command helped defeat Jos\u00b4e de la Serna at the Battle of Ayachucho, leading to his promotion to Marshal. This man helped liberate Ecuador and served under S\u00b4\u0131mon Bolivar. For ten points, name this leader who is the namesake of one of Bolivia\u2019s capitals.", "answer": "Antonio Jos\u00b4e de<b> Sucre</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Israel Stoughton was tasked with capturing a leader in this conflict which led to the Fairfield Swamp Fight. In the prelude to this conflict, John Oldham was killed after landing on Block Island. John Mason led a militia force in this war that surrounded and burned two villages, killing hundreds of women and children, in an attempt to subdue Sassacus. This conflict was ended by the 1638 Treaty of Hartford which created a boundary dispute between Massachusetts and Connecticut. For ten points, name this colonial war which nearly annihilated the namesake Native American tribe.", "answer": "<b> Pequot</b> War", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In<em> The Great Learning</em>, this concept is said to improve humanity by illuminating virtue and in<em> The</em> <em>Doctrine of the Mean</em>, this concept is equated to integrity and sincerity. One text named for this concept argues that the \u201cDoorway of the Mysterious Female\u201d can be used to understand this concept. That text argues that becoming one with this concept requires non-action, or<em> wu-wei</em>. For ten points name this Chinese philosophical concept which translates to \u201cthe Way\u201d and which names a religious tradition represented by Yin-Yang.", "answer": "the<b> Dao</b> (accept the<b> Tao</b>; accept the<b> Way</b> before \u201cname for,\u201d prompt afterward until mentioned.", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This civilization\u2019s Parkin site may have been the city of Casqui that was described by visiting foreigners. Members of this civilization played a ball game called \u201cchunkey,\u201d part of the Southeastern Ceremonial Complex. This civilization was responsible for building a circle of cedar posts called \u201cWoodhenge\u201d as well as the Grand Village and the Emerald Mound. For ten points, identify this pre-Columbian culture in the Americas centered at Cahokia that resided by a namesake river in the South.", "answer": "<b> Mississippi</b>an culture", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A faceless woman in a hat stands next to a girl in white sitting on curving branches in this artist\u2019s <em>In the Apple Tree</em>. This artist became the highest priced female artist in 2013 when<em> After Lunch</em> sold for $10.9 million. A woman in a white dress stands with her back turned to the viewer and wears a black collar in one of this artist\u2019s works. This artist of<em> Lady at Her Toilette</em> painted her sister Edna gazing down at a sleeping baby behind a veil curtain. For ten points, name this female Impressionist artist of<em> The</em> <em>Cradle</em>.", "answer": "Berthe<b> Morisot</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The supposed death of a student named Martin Smid helped spark this event, despite later evidence suggesting that Petr Uhl passed the false rumor to Radio Free Europe. The</b> <b>Civic Forum was established during this event by members of (+)</b> <b>Charter 77, who used</b> <b>jingling keys as a symbol of openness. Ethnic differences between this event\u2019s participants resulted in a similar-named (*)</b> \u201cdivorce\u201d four years later. Shortly after this event, the Federal Assembly unanimously elected Vaclav Havel as its country\u2019s president. For ten points, name this nonviolent 1989 event that resulted in the collapse of total communist rule in Czechoslovakia.", "answer": "<b> Velvet</b> Revolution or<b> Gentle</b> Revolution (do not accept or prompt on Velvet Divorce)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Francis de Groot ambushed a ribbon cutting ceremony in this city just as Premier Jack Lang was about to open a bridge. An arch bridge modeled on the Hell Gate Bridge crosses</b> <b>this city\u2019s harbor which is adorned by a building constructed with (+)</b> <b>concrete shell roof</b> <b>located at Bennelong Point. This city was originally founded by Arthur Phillip, who brought the First Fleet of (*)</b> Convicts. James Cook landed near this city at its Botany Bay. This waterfront of this city features a Jorn Utzon designed opera house. Serving as the capital of New South Wales, for ten points, name this largest city in Australia.", "answer": "<b> Sydney</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>One ruler of this dynasty was crowned by his wasita Barjawan after being told to climb down from a sycamore tree. Jawhar the Sicilian founded the capital of this dynasty, where</b> <b>a non-Abbasid \u201cHouse of Knowledge\u201d was built by a ruler who forced (+)</b> <b>Jews to wear</b> <b>bells and burned the Church of the Holy Sepulchre. That ruler is revered by the Druze and was known as the \u201cMad Caliph.\u201d The Ayyubids under (*)</b> Saladin followed this dynasty, which established the al-Azhar University in its capital, built on the previous site of al-Fustat. For ten points, name this Muslim dynasty in Egypt named after a daughter of Muhammad.", "answer": "<b> Fatimid</b> Dynasty (accept<b> Fatimid</b> Caliphate or al-Fatimiyun or<b> Fatimids</b> or Al-Khilafah al-Fatimiyya) Page 10", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Marx claimed that this practice transformed subsistence into profit and created surplus labor, while E. P. Thompson declared that this practice was \u201cclass robbery.\u201d Sir Thomas Tresham\u2019s participation in this practice led to the Newton Rebellion. In response to this</b> <b>practice, a camp at Mousehold Heath was set up by Robert (+)</b> <b>Kett and his followers.</b> <b>Authorized in the Statutes of Merton and Westminster, this practice, which led to the (*) </b>Agricultural Revolution, ended the open field system and increased English wool production. For ten points, name this practice in England where common land was bought and privatised.", "answer": "<b> Enclosure</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Recent protests in this country against its president, nicknamed \u201cIKB,\u201d were sparked</b> <b>by a massacre which left over 100 dead in this country\u2019s Fulani village of (+)</b> <b>Ogassagou.</b> <b>In 2015, 220 hostages were taken in a terrorist attack on the Radisson Blu in this country\u2019s capital. The MNLA lost control of the north of this country to Ansar Dine after attempting to make (*) </b> Azawad an independent Tuareg nation. In 2012, Kidal, Gao, and Timbuktu fell in three days to rebels in, for ten points, what West African country whose government rules from Bamako?", "answer": "<b> Mali</b> Page 11", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}